<set><question><matchNum>0</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>CHEMISTRY</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  The reaction of hydrocarbons with oxygen to produce carbon dioxide, water and heat is called:  W)  fission X)  fusion Y)  endothermic Z)  combustion  </problem><solution> Z)  COMBUSTION   </solution></question><question><matchNum>0</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>CHEMISTRY</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  What is the only known substance for which there is no triple point:  </problem><solution> HELIUM     </solution></question><question><matchNum>1</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>PHYSICS</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  What is the name of the device that is made by combining two basic types of solid state rectifiers allowing the device to both rectify and amplify a current?  </problem><solution> TRANSISTOR   </solution></question><question><matchNum>1</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>PHYSICS</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  Which of the following was one of the first direct indications that the speed of light could not be exceeded:  W)  Faradays law of induction X)  Einsteins theory of Special Relativity Y)  the Lorentz-Fitzgerald contraction Z)  Plancks constant  </problem><solution> Y)  THE LORENTZ-FITZGERALD CONTRACTION   Sample Round Robin     Page 1 </solution></question><question><matchNum>2</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>BIOLOGY</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  An example of negative feedback control is when:  W)  the end product of a metabolic pathway inhibits an earlier reaction X)  the initial enzyme of a metabolic pathway inhibits a later reaction Y)  the end product of a metabolic pathway stimulates an earlier reaction Z)  the initial product of a metabolic pathway inhibits the next reaction  </problem><solution> W)  THE END PRODUCT OF A METABOLIC PATHWAY INHIBITS AN EARLIER REACTION    </solution></question><question><matchNum>2</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>BIOLOGY</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  What is the name of the inner surface of the myocardium that is lined with a layer of endothelial cells?  </problem><solution> ENDOCARDIUM     </solution></question><question><matchNum>3</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>ASTRONOMY</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  The hydrogen envelope that surrounds the comets nucleus derives its hydrogen most directly from:   W)  gases escaping from the melting comets ice X)  hydrogen captured from interstellar space Y)  breakdown of water by ultraviolet light Z)  hydrogen in the solar winds  </problem><solution> Y)  BREAKDOWN OF WATER BY ULTRAVIOLET LIGHT  </solution></question><question><matchNum>3</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>ASTRONOMY</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  What do Astronomers call the point in the sky that is directly overhead?  </problem><solution> ZENITH      Sample Round Robin     Page 2 </solution></question><question><matchNum>4</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>MATH</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  Which of the following does NOT yield a periodic non-terminating decimal:     W)  5/6 X)  1/27 Y)  1/18 Z)  7/8  </problem><solution> Z)  7/8    </solution></question><question><matchNum>4</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>MATH</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  What 3 consecutive numbers add up to 45?     </problem><solution>14, 15, AND 16      </solution></question><question><matchNum>5</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>EARTH SCIENCE</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  Which is the best reason for proposing that a boulder lying in an area that was once glaciated is an erratic:  W)  it is of a different composition than the underlying rock X)  it is rounded and worn Y)  it is larger than any surrounding rocks Z)  it is located near a glacial lake  </problem><solution> W)  IT IS OF A DIFFERENT COMPOSITION THAN THE UNDERLYING ROCK   </solution></question><question><matchNum>5</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>EARTH SCIENCE</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  What is the term for groundwater emerging naturally at the ground surface, where the water table intersects the surface:  </problem><solution> SPRING  (ACCEPT:  SEEP) Sample Round Robin     Page 3 </solution></question><question><matchNum>6</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>GENERAL SCIENCE</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  Which of the following is most specifically designed to measure low temperatures:   W)  alcohol thermometer  X)  pyrometer   Y)  cryometer Z)  mercury thermometer    </problem><solution> Y)  CRYOMETER   </solution></question><question><matchNum>6</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>GENERAL SCIENCE</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  Who was the first president of the International Psychoanalysis Association who theorized that the shadow archetype consists of animal instincts:  </problem><solution> CARL JUNG  (Pronounced:  KARL YOUNG)   </solution></question><question><matchNum>7</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>EARTH SCIENCE</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  A tropical storm will be declared a hurricane when:  W)  there is evidence of eye formation X)  wind speeds reach 64 mph Y)  wind gusts are in excess of 74 mph Z)  there is evidence of eye formation and sustained wind speeds of 74 mph   </problem><solution> Z)  THERE IS EVIDENCE OF EYE FORMATION AND SUSTAINED WIND SPEEDS OF 74 MPH    </solution></question><question><matchNum>7</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>EARTH SCIENCE</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  What kind of rocks are formed by the lithification of sediments:  </problem><solution> SEDIMENTARY ROCKS  Sample Round Robin     Page 4 </solution></question><question><matchNum>8</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>CHEMISTRY</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  The ideal fuel for fuel cell use is:  W)  compressed natural gas X)  reformulated gasoline Y)  hydrogen Z)  methanol  </problem><solution> Y)  HYDROGEN   </solution></question><question><matchNum>8</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>CHEMISTRY</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  What is the branch of chemistry that deals with the relationship between electricity and chemical reactions?  </problem><solution> ELECTROCHEMISTRY    </solution></question><question><matchNum>9</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>PHYSICS</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  Which of the following is NOT a consequence of the theory of electromagnetic radiation as formulated by J. C. Maxwell:  W)  electric fields can cause magnetic disturbance X)  electromagnetic radiation consists of an electric and magnetic wave Y)  light is a form of electromagnetic radiation Z)  bright red light ejects no electrons from a metallic surface whereas dim violet light can  </problem><solution> Z)  BRIGHT RED LIGHT EJECTS NO ELECTRONS FROM A METALLIC SURFACE WHEREAS DIM VIOLET LIGHT CAN  </solution></question><question><matchNum>9</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>PHYSICS</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  All elements with an atomic number greater than what number are unstable?  </problem><solution> 83   Sample Round Robin     Page 5 </solution></question><question><matchNum>10</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>BIOLOGY</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  Mendel did most of his original experimentation using this type of plant:  </problem><solution> PEA   </solution></question><question><matchNum>10</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>BIOLOGY</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  Order the following from the part of the digestive tract nearest to the beginning to the part nearest to the end:  jejunum, ileum, esophagus, duodenum    </problem><solution> ESOPHAGUS, DUODENUM, JEJUNUM, ILEUM    </solution></question><question><matchNum>11</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>ASTRONOMY</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  A meteor that reaches the surface of the Earth is more accurately called a:    </problem><solution> METEORITE   </solution></question><question><matchNum>11</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>ASTRONOMY</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  At a location half-way from the Equator to the North Pole, which of the following correctly describes the stars apparent motion:  W)  they move in circles parallel with the horizon X)  they rise and set vertically Y)  they remain stationary Z)  they rise and set at an angle to the horizon  </problem><solution> Z)  THEY RISE AND SET AT AN ANGLE TO THE HORIZON Sample Round Robin     Page 6 </solution></question><question><matchNum>12</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>MATH</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  In a simple random sample:  W)  response bias will be small X)  non-response bias will be small Y)  any two samples of the same size will have the same chance of being drawn Z)  each subject is asked every question and random responses are allowed  </problem><solution> Y)  ANY TWO SAMPLES OF THE SAME SIZE WILL HAVE THE SAME CHANCE OF BEING DRAWN   </solution></question><question><matchNum>12</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>MATH</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  Every even integer greater than 2 can be written as the sum of two primes. Give the respective two pairs of prime numbers that when added give 8 and 12:   </problem><solution> 5 AND 3 FOR THE NUMBER 8;  AND  7 AND 5 FOR THE NUMBER 12   [Note: 11 and 1 is not an acceptable answer;  1 is not a prime number]      </solution></question><question><matchNum>13</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>EARTH SCIENCE</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  What is the professional name for the person who studies fossils?  </problem><solution> PALEONTOLOGIST  (pronounced:  pale-ee-on-TALL-o-gist)   </solution></question><question><matchNum>13</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>EARTH SCIENCE</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  Which of the following latitudes and dates would coincide with the longest duration of insolation:  W)  23  South on September 21 X)  50 North on June 21 Y)  50 South on March 21 Z)  0 on June 21  </problem><solution>X)  50 NORTH ON JUNE 21  (Solution:  W=12 hrs;  X=15 hrs;  Y= 12 hrs;  Z=12 hrs)   Sample Round Robin     Page 7 </solution></question><question><matchNum>14</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>GENERAL SCIENCE</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  In the tempering of steel tools, the process of rapidly cooling the tool is called:   W)  quickening   X)  quenching   Y)  drawing Z)  case hardening  </problem><solution> X)  QUENCHING   </solution></question><question><matchNum>14</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>GENERAL SCIENCE</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  What is the general name of the unusual infectious agents that causes spongiform (pronounced:  SPONGE-ih-form) encephalopathy (pronounced:  EN-seff-a-lop-o-thee)?  </problem><solution> PRIONS    </solution></question><question><matchNum>15</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>ASTRONOMY</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  Which of the following planets has the highest escape velocity:   W)  Saturn X)  Uranus Y)  Jupiter Z)  Mars  </problem><solution> Y)  JUPITER   </solution></question><question><matchNum>15</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>ASTRONOMY</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  Which moon is the only other body in our solar system, besides the Earth, that has an atmosphere of mostly nitrogen?  </problem><solution> TITAN  Sample Round Robin     Page 8 </solution></question><question><matchNum>16</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>CHEMISTRY</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  Out of the following choices, which is the correct name for N2O3:  W)  dinitrogen oxide X)  dinitrogen dioxide Y)  dinitrogen trioxide Z)  dinitrogen tetroxide  </problem><solution> Y)  DINITROGEN TRIOXIDE  </solution></question><question><matchNum>16</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>CHEMISTRY</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  Convert 673 Kelvin into degrees centigrade:  </problem><solution> 400C  (Solution:  673-273=400)      </solution></question><question><matchNum>17</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>PHYSICS</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  In stars, the fusion of hydrogen typically releases energy as:  W)  photons and friction X)  photons and neutrinos Y)  photons and mesons Z)  photons and gravitons  </problem><solution> X)  PHOTONS AND NEUTRINOS   </solution></question><question><matchNum>17</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>PHYSICS</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  Assuming friction is negligible, if a lever has a mechanical advantage of  5, how much effort in newtons is needed to lift a 10 newton load?  </problem><solution>  2 NEWTONS  ( Solution:  Force = resistance / mechanical advantage )  Sample Round Robin     Page 9 </solution></question><question><matchNum>18</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>BIOLOGY</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  Which of the following is the term for when a segment of a chromosome rotates 180 degrees and rejoins the same chromosome:   W)  deletion X)  inversion Y)  translocation Z)  duplication  </problem><solution> X)  INVERSION   </solution></question><question><matchNum>18</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>BIOLOGY</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  Germs that cause fever usually act on this section of the brain, which is sometimes referred to as the bodys thermostat:  </problem><solution> HYPOTHALAMUS    </solution></question><question><matchNum>19</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>ASTRONOMY</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  Light from distant galaxies comes mostly from which of the following:  W)  low mass stars X)  high mass stars Y)  ionized hydrogen nebula Z)  large globular clusters of stars   </problem><solution> X)  HIGH MASS STARS   </solution></question><question><matchNum>19</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>ASTRONOMY</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  Which planet in our solar system has the most circular orbit?  </problem><solution> VENUS  Sample Round Robin     Page 10 </solution></question><question><matchNum>20</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>MATH</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  In 1700 AD, this person showed that a series of 0s and 1s could be used to denote a number:  </problem><solution> GOTTFRIED LIEBNIZ   </solution></question><question><matchNum>20</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>MATH</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  If perfect numbers, except 6, can be expressed by the sum of the cubes of an unbroken sequence of consecutive odd integers, what are the consecutive odd integers which, when cubed, give the perfect number 28?    </problem><solution> 13 + 33  (Solution: 13 + 33 = 28)      </solution></question><question><matchNum>21</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>GENERAL SCIENCE</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  Which of the following is responsible for the changing of  the seasons in North America:  W)  the Earth's orbit is elliptical X)  the Sun moves through space Y)  the Earth's axis is not perpendicular to the ecliptic Z)  the Earth's axis precesses  </problem><solution> Y)  THE EARTH'S AXIS IS NOT PERPENDICULAR TO THE ECLIPTIC   </solution></question><question><matchNum>21</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>GENERAL SCIENCE</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem> Which of the following most closely approximates the weight of a 1999 United States nickel:                       W)  1.9 grams X)  2.9 grams  Y)  5.9 grams Z)  8.9 grams   </problem><solution> Y)  5.9 GRAMS  Sample Round Robin     Page 11 </solution></question><question><matchNum>22</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>CHEMISTRY</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  Which of the following is an example of a buffer system:  W)  H2CO3 and water X)  H2CO3 and NaHCO3 Y)  NH3 and N2 Z)  NaCl  and KCl  </problem><solution> X)  H2CO3 AND NaHCO3    </solution></question><question><matchNum>22</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>CHEMISTRY</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  Convert -40F into Centigrade:  </problem><solution> -40C     </solution></question><question><matchNum>23</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>PHYSICS</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  Which of the following particles has not yet been observed but is generally theorized to exist:  W)  mesons X)  gluons Y)  fermionic hadrons Z)  gravitons  </problem><solution> Z)  GRAVITONS   </solution></question><question><matchNum>23</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>PHYSICS</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  With regard to the speed at which sound travels in a specific medium, at standard temperature and pressure, order the following materials from the SLOWEST to the FASTEST:  steel, wood, air, water.  </problem><solution> AIR, WATER, WOOD, STEEL  (Solution:  air~331 m/sec;  water~500 m/sec;  wood~4300 m/sec;  steel~5000 m/sec)  Sample Round Robin     Page 12 Sample Round Robin     Page 13 </solution></question><question><matchNum>24</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>TOSS-UP</type><pointVal>4</pointVal><topic>BIOLOGY</topic><format>Multiple Choice</format><problem>  A newborn babys immunity, which is acquired from the mother, is often referred to as:  W)  active immunity X)  passive immunity Y)  bistander immunity Z)  physical immunity  </problem><solution> X)  PASSIVE IMMUNITY   </solution></question><question><matchNum>24</matchNum><origin>Arizona</origin><type>BONUS</type><pointVal>10</pointVal><topic>BIOLOGY</topic><format>Short Answer</format><problem>  Parkinsons disease is caused by a lack of this neurotransmitter in the brain:  </problem><solution> DOPAMINE      </solution></question></set>